<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>coffee on Recipes</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/coffee/</link><description>Recent content in coffee on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/coffee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chemex coffee</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chemex-coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chemex-coffee/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 g coffee 510 ml water Instructions Heat water to 91°C. Grind coffee beans on a coarse setting. Place filter the top of the Chemex, pre-soak with hot water, and discard the water. Place the grounds into the filter. Tare scale, start a timer, and circle pour 60 ml of water onto the grounds and bloom the coffee for 30 seconds. After the bloom, pour 50ml of water in a circular motion.</description></item><item><title>Stovetop espresso</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/stovetop-espresso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/stovetop-espresso/</guid><description>Ingredients 21 g coffee water Instructions Finely grind coffee. Add boiling water up to below the pressure release valve. Add coffee to basket but don&amp;rsquo;t tamp. Put on small stove burner. Allow to percolate but pull off when the stream turns from golden brown to pale yellow. Notes This should make about 100 ml of coffee.</description></item><item><title>V60 pourover</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/v60-pourover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/v60-pourover/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 g coffee 500 g water Instructions Boil kettle, grind coffee, add paper filter to V60 and set it over the carafe over scales. Wet the filter and let it drain into the carafe warming it. Discard the water. Add coffee, and form a well. Tare the scales. Start the timer and pour in 60 g, swirl the V60, and let the coffee &amp;ldquo;bloom&amp;rdquo; for 45 seconds.</description></item></channel></rss>