<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>soup on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/soup/</link><description>Recent content in soup on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/soup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cannellini, potato, and spinach soup</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/cannellini-potato-and-spinach-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/cannellini-potato-and-spinach-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 cans cannellini or other white beans 2 large potato, diced 1 small onion, chopped 2 garlic cloves 2 cups water 1 stock cube 2 cups baby spinach 1 handful Italian flat parsley, chopped 2 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1/4 tsp chilli flakes 1/2 tsp salt Instructions Rinse your beans under runny water and drain, you want to remove the cloudy water. In a large pot heat gently 1 Tbsp of extra virgin olive oil and add 1 chopped garlic clove (keep the other one for the dressing), onion, chilli and cook for about 3 minutes or until the onion starts to soften.</description></item><item><title>Pea and ham soup</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/pea-and-ham-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/pea-and-ham-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 ham hock 500 g green split peas 1-2 onions, chopped 2-3 carrots, chopped 3-4 celery sticks, chopped 2 potatoes, chopped 2-3 bay leaves Garnish
parsley, finely chopped bread Instructions Place the ham hock in the pressure cooker and cover with water. Cook for 45 minutes on high with natural steam release. After the pressure is released, take out ham hock and shred or chop the meat.</description></item><item><title>Vegetarian soy-milk ramen</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/vegetarian-soy-milk-ramen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/vegetarian-soy-milk-ramen/</guid><description>Ingredients Dashi
¾ cup water 1 piece kombu (dried kelp) (1&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot;, 2.5 cm x 5 cm) 1 dried shiitake mushroom Soup
1 Tbsp toasted white sesame seeds 2 cloves garlic ½ inch ginger green onion/scallion (use white part) 2 tsp sesame oil (roasted) 2 tsp doubanjiang (spicy chili bean paste) 2 tsp miso 1 Tbsp sake 2 tsp soy sauce 1 cup unsweetened soy milk ½ cup dashi ¼ tsp kosher/sea salt Dash white pepper powder Ramen</description></item><item><title>Wedding soup</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/wedding-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/wedding-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1 large leek, finely sliced 2 garlic cloves, minced 2 celery stalks, diced 2 bay leaves 2 litres chicken stock 150 g small pasta, such as orzo, acini di pepe 1 bunch greens, such as curly endive or kale (cavalo nero), roughly chopped lemon, to serve Meatballs
500 g mince, such as pork, chicken, or a mix ½ cup breadcrumbs, wetted with some milk 2 garlic cloves, minced 25-50 g grated parmesan ½ cup fresh chopped herbs, such as chives, parsley, sage ½ tsp dried oregano 1 egg salt and black pepper Instructions Preheat the oven to 200˚C.</description></item></channel></rss>