<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>beef on Recipes</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/ingredients/beef/</link><description>Recent content in beef on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/ingredients/beef/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beef cheek stew</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/beef-cheek-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/beef-cheek-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 3kg beef cheeks 100ml olive oil 2 brown onions, chopped 1 whole head of garlic, split 2 carrots, chopped 1/4 bunch thyme 3 fresh bay leaves 1 cinnamon stick 2 star anise 1lt Pedro Ximenez sherry 500ml red wine Instructions Heat oven to 200C. Clean sinew from beef cheeks, season with sea salt and place cheeks on a baking tray. Bake in oven for about 10 minutes each side.</description></item><item><title>Beef rendang</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/beef-rendang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/beef-rendang/</guid><description>Ingredients 600 g beef chuck steak or gravy beef 1 teaspoon salt 2 teaspoons sugar 1.5 teaspoons tamarind paste 120 g desiccated coconut, toasted in a dry pan Spice paste
2 large onions 3 large jalapeno chillies 14 dried chillies (or fewer if you want it less spicy) 1 thumb sized piece of ginger 2 slices galangal (you can use dried slices - just re hydrate the slices in some hot water for 10 minutes or so) 3 fat cloves of garlic 2 tablespoons of the toasted coconut from above Curry sauce</description></item><item><title>Chilli con carne</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/chilli-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/chilli-con-carne/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tbsp olive oil 3 garlic cloves, minced 1 onion, diced 1 red capsicum, diced 500 g beef mince 3 tbsp tomato paste 800 g can crushed tomato 420 g can red kidney beans 2 beef stock cubes 1 1/2 tsp sugar 125 - 375 ml water Salt and pepper Spice mix
1 - 2 tsp cayenne pepper (adjust to taste) 4 tsp paprika powder 5 tsp cumin powder 2 tsp garlic powder (or onion powder) 2 tsp onion powder 2 tsp oregano To serve</description></item><item><title>Mapo tofu (Japanese-style)</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/mapo-tofu-japanese-style/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/mapo-tofu-japanese-style/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cloves garlic 1 inch ginger (2.5 cm) 2 green onions/scallions 400 g silken/soft tofu 1 Tbsp neutral-flavored oil (vegetable, canola, etc) 225 g ground pork (or any other meat/veggies of your choice) Seasonings
2 ½ Tbsp doubanjiang (spicy chili bean sauce/broad bean paste) or 1 ½ Tbsp Doubanjiang (non-spicy) and 1 Tbsp Ladoubanjigang (spicy) 2 Tbsp mirin 1 Tbsp miso 1 Tbsp oyster sauce ½ Tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp sesame oil (roasted) 1 tsp potato starch/cornstarch 4 Tbsp water Instructions Gather all the ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Reverse braised beef</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/reverse-braised-beef/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/reverse-braised-beef/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 kg beef chuck or oyster blade 1 tbsp vinegar 1 tbsp sugar 1 tsp soy sauce oil salt pepper Instructions Place the meat in the pressure cooker. Pour in enough water to almost cover the meat, and cook on high pressure for 45 minutes with natural steam release. Gently fish the meat out of the pan, breaking it up as little as possible, and let the pieces dry/steam-off on paper towels for a few minutes.</description></item></channel></rss>