<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Eat on Recipes</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/</link><description>Recent content in Eat on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baja fish tacos</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/baja-fish-tacos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/baja-fish-tacos/</guid><description>Ingredients Cabbage slaw
5 cups (or one 10-ounce bag) shredded red cabbage 3 tablespoons minced red onion 1/2 cup fresh chopped cilantro 3 tablespoons cider vinegar 1-1/2 teaspoons vegetable oil 1/2 teaspoon salt Chipotle sauce
3/4 cup mayonnaise, best quality such as Hellmann&amp;rsquo;s 2 tablespoons lime juice, from one lime 2-3 chipotle chiles in adobo sauce (canned), roughly chopped, plus 1-2 teaspoons sauce (see note below) 1 large garlic clove, roughly chopped Beer batter</description></item><item><title>Beef cheek stew</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/beef-cheek-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/beef-cheek-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 3kg beef cheeks 100ml olive oil 2 brown onions, chopped 1 whole head of garlic, split 2 carrots, chopped 1/4 bunch thyme 3 fresh bay leaves 1 cinnamon stick 2 star anise 1lt Pedro Ximenez sherry 500ml red wine Instructions In a heavy-based pot, heat olive oil, season beef cheeks with salt and pepper, and brown well. Remove from the pan. Add onion, garlic head and carrots to caramelise.</description></item><item><title>Beef rendang</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/beef-rendang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/beef-rendang/</guid><description>Ingredients 600 g beef chuck steak or gravy beef 1 teaspoon salt 2 teaspoons sugar 1.5 teaspoons tamarind paste 120 g desiccated coconut, toasted in a dry pan Spice paste
2 large onions 3 large jalapeno chillies 14 dried chillies (or fewer if you want it less spicy) 1 thumb sized piece of ginger 2 slices galangal (you can use dried slices - just re hydrate the slices in some hot water for 10 minutes or so) 3 fat cloves of garlic 2 tablespoons of the toasted coconut from above Curry sauce</description></item><item><title>Bengali rice porridge with lentils and chicken</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/bengali-rice-porridge-with-lentils-and-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/bengali-rice-porridge-with-lentils-and-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 3/4 cup jasmine rice 1 inch fresh turmeric or 1 teaspoon dried turmeric 1 inch fresh ginger 2 tablespoons butter or ghee 1/2 teaspoon Kashmiri red chilli powder 1/4 cup red lentils 6 cups (1.5 L) chicken stock 2 medium potato, peeled, 1 cm dice 400 g chicken thighs Coriander chutney
1/2 bunch coriander, finely chopped 2 Thai green chiles, finely chopped 2 tablespoons (30 mL) lime juice 2 tablespoons (30 mL) olive oil To serve</description></item><item><title>Black bean burgers</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/black-bean-burgers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/black-bean-burgers/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 (15-ounce) cans black beans, rinsed and drained 4 tablespoons vegetable oil, divided 1 medium onion, finely chopped (about 1 cup) 1 large poblano pepper, finely chopped (about 1 cup) 3 medium cloves garlic, minced 1 chipotle chile in adobo sauce, finely chopped, plus 1 teaspoon sauce 3/4 cup roasted cashews 1/2 cup finely crumbled feta or cotija cheese 2 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 whole egg 3/4 cup panko bread crumbs Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper Cheese as desired, such as pepper jack, cheddar, muenster, or Swiss (optional) 6 to 8 hearty hamburger buns, toasted Condiments as desired, such as chipotle mayonnaise, ketchup, mustard, or mayonnaise (optional) Toppings as desired, such as shredded lettuce, sliced onions, and pickles (optional) Instructions Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat oven to 350°F.</description></item><item><title>Black beans</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/black-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/black-beans/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 x 400g cans of black beans 1 onion, chopped 3-4 garlic cloves, minced 2 tsp cumin 2 tsp ancho chili 2 bay leaves salt coriander leaves Instructions Saute onion in oil in a saucepan on medium heat until softened. Add garlic and cook for a couple of minutes. Fry dried spices for a couple of minutes until fragrant. Rinse beans then add them to the pot and cover with water.</description></item><item><title>Broccoli pasta</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/broccoli-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/broccoli-pasta/</guid><description>Ingredients 200 g short pasta 1 broccoli, cut into small florets ½-1 cup grated parmesan zest of 1 lemon about 2 tbsp lemon juice 5 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 2 garlic cloves, minced ½ tsp chili flakes salt and pepper extra parmesan Instructions Add pasta to boiling salted water. While pasta is cooking, fry off garlic and chili flakes in the oil for a minute or so until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Cannellini, potato, and spinach soup</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/cannellini-potato-and-spinach-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/cannellini-potato-and-spinach-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 cans cannellini or other white beans 2 large potato, diced 1 small onion, chopped 2 garlic cloves 2 cups water 1 stock cube 2 cups baby spinach 1 handful Italian flat parsley, chopped 2 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1/4 tsp chilli flakes 1/2 tsp salt Instructions Rinse your beans under runny water and drain, you want to remove the cloudy water. In a large pot heat gently 1 Tbsp of extra virgin olive oil and add 1 chopped garlic clove (keep the other one for the dressing), onion, chilli and cook for about 3 minutes or until the onion starts to soften.</description></item><item><title>Cauliflower puree</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/cauliflower-puree/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/cauliflower-puree/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 medium cauliflower head 50g butter 185ml thickened cream Instructions Chop cauliflower florets off central stalk, discard stalk then slice florets finely. Heat butter and cream in a heavy-based pot, add cauliflower, mix well and cover with a lid. Simmer for about 35 minutes or until soft. Puree until smooth and check seasoning. Store with baking paper on top to stop a skin forming. Notes Recipe derived from Good Food.</description></item><item><title>Channa masala</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/channa-masala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/channa-masala/</guid><description>Ingredients 4 medium cloves garlic, roughly chopped 1 (1-inch) knob ginger, peeled, roughly chopped 1 to 6 green Thai chiles (to taste), roughly chopped 2 tablespoons (30ml) juice from 1 lemon, divided Kosher salt 2 tablespoons (30ml) vegetable oil or ghee 2 teaspoons (8g) black mustard seed 1 teaspoon (4g) whole cumin seed 1 large onion, finely diced (about 1 1/2 cups; 300g) 2 teaspoons (8g) ground coriander 1/2 teaspoon (2g) freshly ground black pepper 1/2 teaspoon (2g) ground turmeric 1 1/2 teaspoons (6g) store-bought or homemade garam masala, divided 1 (14-ounce) can whole peeled tomatoes 2 (14-ounce) cans chickpeas, drained and rinsed 1 cup cilantro leaves, roughly chopped (1 ounce; 25g) Instructions Combine garlic, ginger, chiles, 1 tablespoon lemon juice, and 1/2 teaspoon kosher salt in a mortar and pestle or in the small work bowl of a food processor and pound or process until a fine paste is produced.</description></item><item><title>Chemex coffee</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chemex-coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chemex-coffee/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 g coffee 510 ml water Instructions Heat water to 91°C. Grind coffee beans on a coarse setting. Place filter the top of the Chemex, pre-soak with hot water, and discard the water. Place the grounds into the filter. Tare scale, start a timer, and circle pour 60 ml of water onto the grounds and bloom the coffee for 30 seconds. After the bloom, pour 50ml of water in a circular motion.</description></item><item><title>Chicken and mushroom risotto</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chicken-and-mushroom-risotto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chicken-and-mushroom-risotto/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tbsp olive oil 400 g chicken thigh fillets 400 g mushrooms, sliced 2 tbsp / 30 g butter 2 garlic cloves, minced 1 onion, finely diced ½ cup / 125 ml white wine 250 g arborio risotto rice 1 L chicken stock 35 g freshly grated parmesan cheese 25-50 g butter parsley, chopped Instructions Heat oil in a wide pot or skillet over high heat, cook chicken thighs, then set aside.</description></item><item><title>Chicken teriyaki</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chicken-teriyaki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chicken-teriyaki/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 inch ginger, grated 500 g boneless, skin-on chicken thighs salt and pepper 1 Tbsp neutral oil 2 Tbsp sake Teriyaki sauce
1 Tbsp sake 1 Tbsp mirin 1 Tbsp sugar 2 Tbsp soy sauce 2 Tbsp water Instructions In a large bowl, combine the grated ginger, including the juices. Add all the ingredients for teriyaki sauce in the bowl and mix together. If the thighs are very thick on one side, flatten them to an even thickness with a meat mallet/tenderizer.</description></item><item><title>Chicken with cardamom rice</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chicken-with-cardamom-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chicken-with-cardamom-rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 25g barberries or currants 4 tbsp olive oil 2 onions, sliced 1 kg chicken thighs with bone and skin 10 cardamom pods 1/3 tsp whole cloves 2 cinnamon sticks 300 g basmati rice 550 ml boiling water 5g parsley 5g dill 5g coriander 100g Greek yogurt, mixed with 2 tbsp olive oil Instructions Put the sugar in a small saucepan along with 40ml of water and heat until the sugar dissolves.</description></item><item><title>Chickpea coconut curry</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chickpea-coconut-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chickpea-coconut-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients ¼ cup oil 4 garlic cloves, chopped 1 large yellow onion, chopped 1 (2-inch) piece ginger, finely chopped Kosher salt and black pepper 1 teaspoons ground turmeric 1 teaspoon red-pepper flakes 3 (400 g) cans chickpeas, drained and rinsed 2 (400 g) cans full-fat coconut milk 2 cups vegetable or chicken stock or water 1 bunch Swiss chard, kale or collard greens, stems removed, torn into bite-size pieces 1 cup mint leaves, for serving Toasted pita, lavash or other flatbread, for serving (optional) Instructions Heat oil in a large pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Chickpeas (pressure cooker)</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chickpeas-pressure-cooker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chickpeas-pressure-cooker/</guid><description>Ingredients 450 g dried chickpeas 6 cups water 1 teaspoon fine sea salt 1 small onion, peeled and halved 2 garlic cloves, peeled 2 bay leaves Instructions Check chickpeas for stones and dirt clods. Rinse the chickpeas, then put them in the pressure cooker. Add the water, onion, garlic, and bay leaves. Cook on high pressure for 45 minutes with a natural steam release. Notes Recipe derived from Mike Vrobel at Dad Cooks Dinner.</description></item><item><title>Chilli con carne</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chilli-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chilli-con-carne/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tbsp olive oil 3 garlic cloves, minced 1 onion, diced 1 red capsicum, diced 500 g beef mince 3 tbsp tomato paste 800 g can crushed tomato 420 g can red kidney beans 2 beef stock cubes 1 1/2 tsp sugar 125 - 375 ml water Salt and pepper Spice mix
1 - 2 tsp cayenne pepper (adjust to taste) 4 tsp paprika powder 5 tsp cumin powder 2 tsp garlic powder (or onion powder) 2 tsp onion powder 2 tsp oregano To serve</description></item><item><title>Chilli con veggie</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chilli-con-veggie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chilli-con-veggie/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 medium onions 4 cloves of garlic 1 medium leek 1 long fresh red chilli 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 tablespoons ground cumin 2 tablespoons ground coriander 2 tablespoons smoked paprika ½ a cinnamon stick, or 1 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2 tablespoons dried oregano 1 whole nutmeg , for grating 2 tablespoons tomato purée 250 g dried green lentils 250 g dried red lentils 2 x 400 g tins of red kidney beans 2 x 400 g tins of black beans 2 x 400 g tins of chopped tomatoes 1.</description></item><item><title>Double coriander chicken</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/double-coriander-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/double-coriander-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tbsp vegetable oil 3 garlic cloves, roughly chopped 2 coriander plants, stalks and roots roughly chopped, leaves reserved 1 tbsp ground coriander 4 chicken thighs, cut into 3 cm pieces 1 long green chilli, thickly sliced 1-2 tbsp fish sauce 250 ml (1 cup) coconut cream steamed rice and lime wedges, to serve Instructions Heat a wok over high heat and add the vegetable oil. Add the garlic and coriander stalks and roots and stir-fry for about 1 minute or until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Falafel</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/falafel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/falafel/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 pound dried chickpeas (1 generous cup; 225g) 2 ounces picked fresh cilantro, parsley, or mint leaves, or preferably a mixture of all three (about 2 cups; 55g) 6 scallions, white and pale green parts only, sliced (about 2 ounces; 55g) 2 medium cloves garlic, minced (about 2 teaspoons; 10ml) 1 teaspoon (about 4g) ground cumin 1/2 teaspoon (about 2g) ground coriander seed 2 teaspoons (about 10g) kosher salt, plus more for seasoning 2 to 3 cups (480 to 720ml) vegetable oil, for frying Tahini sauce and Hummus for serving Instructions Rinse chickpeas and place in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Fish potato cakes</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/fish-potato-cakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/fish-potato-cakes/</guid><description>Ingredients 700 g potatoes, peeled and chopped 500 g salmon (or white fish) fillets ½ cup flat-leaf parsley leaves, finely chopped 1 tablespoon dill, finely chopped 1 tablespoon Dijon mustard, plus extra to serve 1 egg, lightly beaten 1 teaspoon finely grated lemon rind sea salt and cracked black pepper 2 cups (140g) panko breadcrumbs vegetable oil, for shallow-frying Instructions Boil potatoes in salted water until tender. Drain well, place in a large bowl and mash.</description></item><item><title>Fried cauliflower</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/fried-cauliflower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/fried-cauliflower/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 L peanut oil 1/2 cup cornstarch 1/2 cup all purpose flour 1/2 teaspoon baking powder Kosher salt 1/2 cup water 1/2 cup vodka 1 head cauliflower, cut into 1-inch florets 1/3 cup hot sauce, such as Frank&amp;rsquo;s 1 medium clove garlic, minced 1/4 cup picked celery leaves (optional) Instructions Preheat oil to 350°F in a large wok, Dutch oven, or deep fryer. Combine cornstarch, flour, baking powder, and 2 teaspoons kosher salt in a large bowl and whisk until homogeneous.</description></item><item><title>Halal-cart chicken rice</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/halal-cart-chicken-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/halal-cart-chicken-rice/</guid><description>Ingredients Chicken
2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice 1 tablespoon chopped fresh oregano 1/2 teaspoon ground coriander seed 3 garlic cloves, roughly chopped (about 1 1/2 tablespoons) 1/4 cup light olive oil Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper 2 pounds boneless, skinless chicken thighs, trimmed of excess fat (6 to 8 thighs) 1 tablespoon vegetable or canola oil Rice
2 tablespoons unsalted butter 1/2 teaspoon turmeric 1/4 teaspoon ground cumin 1 1/2 cups long-grain or Basmati rice 2 1/2 cups chicken broth Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper Sauce</description></item><item><title>Honey ricotta turnovers</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/honey-ricotta-turnovers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/honey-ricotta-turnovers/</guid><description>Ingredients 3/4 cup whole-milk ricotta 3 tablespoons sugar 1/4 teaspoon pure vanilla extract 1 teaspoon lemon or orange zest (optional) 1 large egg Coarse salt 1/4 cup ( 1/2 stick) unsalted butter 2 tablespoons honey, plus more for serving 6 sheets frozen phyllo dough, thawed Instructions Preheat oven to 350 degrees. In a small bowl, combine ricotta, sugar, vanilla, zest (if using), egg, and pinch of salt. Mix well to combine.</description></item><item><title>Karaage</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/karaage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/karaage/</guid><description>Ingredients 600g chicken thighs, skin-on 3 tbsp light soy sauce 2 tbsp sake 1 tbsp grated ginger, juice only ½ tsp sugar ¾ cup potato flour (or substitute cornflour) about 2L canola, sunflower or other vegetable oil, for deep frying Japanese mayonnaise, to serve lemon slices, to serve shichimi togarashi (Japanese seven-spice), to serve (optional) Instructions Cut the chicken into 5cm pieces. Combine the chicken with the soy sauce, sake, ginger juice and sugar and stand for 10 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Lamb, chickpea and dried fruit stew</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/lamb-chickpea-and-dried-fruit-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/lamb-chickpea-and-dried-fruit-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons oil or butter 800 g lamb stew meat (shoulder, leg or shank) cut onto 1 ½ inch cubes 1 onion, diced 5 garlic cloves, rough chopped 1 teaspoon of each: salt, pepper, cumin, coriander, turmeric, cinnamon, and cumin seeds (seeds are optional, add another teaspoon ground cumin if no seeds) ½ teaspoon chilli flakes (Aleppo chilli flakes are nice) and more for garnish 2 tablespoons tomato paste ¼ cup apple cider vinegar (or red wine vinegar) 2 tablespoons honey or brown sugar 1 1/4 cups chicken stock or broth 1 x 400 g can chickpeas, rinsed and drained ¼ cup raisins or dried apricots (chopped), or even dried currants A few bay leaves, and thyme and rosemary sprigs 1-2 teaspoons butter 1-2 teaspoons flour Instructions Brown the meat in cast iron pan.</description></item><item><title>Mapo tofu (Japanese-style)</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/mapo-tofu-japanese-style/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/mapo-tofu-japanese-style/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cloves garlic 1 inch ginger (2.5 cm) 2 green onions/scallions 400 g silken/soft tofu 1 Tbsp neutral-flavored oil (vegetable, canola, etc) 225 g ground pork (or any other meat/veggies of your choice) Seasonings
2 ½ Tbsp doubanjiang (spicy chili bean sauce/broad bean paste) or 1 ½ Tbsp Doubanjiang (non-spicy) and 1 Tbsp Ladoubanjigang (spicy) 2 Tbsp mirin 1 Tbsp miso 1 Tbsp oyster sauce ½ Tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp sesame oil (roasted) 1 tsp potato starch/cornstarch 4 Tbsp water Instructions Gather all the ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Mas riha (Maldivian fish curry)</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/mas-riha-maldivian-fish-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/mas-riha-maldivian-fish-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tbsp coconut oil 4 cloves garlic, minced 2 cardamom pods 1″ fresh ginger, peeled and sliced into matchsticks 10 curry leaves (1 tsp curry powder okay) 1 jalapeño or other green chile (serrano, etc), stem, seeds, and ribs removed, sliced 1 onion, sliced 1/2 tsp each ground fennel, cumin, turmeric, black pepper 1 can coconut milk (14 oz) 1 cinnamon stick salt to taste (about 1 tsp) 1 lb fresh tuna or other firm fish (mahi mahi, swordfish, etc), cut into cubes and lightly salted Instructions Lightly salt the fish and set it aside.</description></item><item><title>Melanzane alla Parmigiana (eggplant Parmesan)</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/melanzane-alla-parmigiana-eggplant-parmesan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/melanzane-alla-parmigiana-eggplant-parmesan/</guid><description>Ingredients Olive oil, vegetable oil, or a combination, for frying 1 kg eggplant, sliced 1/4 inch thick Salt 1 1/4 cups (360ml) tomato sauce (see note) 3/4 pound shredded fresh mozzarella (12 ounces; 340g) Torn fresh oregano leaves, from about 4 sprigs Instructions Preheat oven to 200°C. Fill a large cast iron skillet with 1/2 inch oil and heat over high heat until shimmering. Working in batches, fry eggplant slices, turning, until browned on both sides, about 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Mushroom and sausage pasta bake</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/mushroom-and-sausage-pasta-bake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/mushroom-and-sausage-pasta-bake/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup Panko-style bread crumbs 6 ounces grated Parmesan cheese 1/4 cup chopped fresh parsley leaves 2 tablespoons finely minced fresh chives 2 small shallots, finely minced (about 1/2 cup) 2 medium cloves garlic, minced (about 2 teaspoons) 2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper 2 tablespoons unsalted butter 8 ounces Italian sausage (mild or hot), removed from casings 1 pound mixed mushrooms (such as portobello, shiitake, and oyster), cleaned and thinly sliced 1 tablespoon soy sauce 1 tablespoon juice from 1 lemon 2 1/2 tablespoons all-purpose flour 2 cups homemade or store-bought low-sodium chicken stock 1 cup heavy cream 12 ounces fresh or 8 ounces dried ridged pasta such as rotini or campanelle Instructions Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and keep at a bare simmer.</description></item><item><title>Oyakodon</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/oyakodon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/oyakodon/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 boneless skinless chicken thighs ½ onion 2 large eggs Seasonings
⅔ cup dashi 1 ½ Tbsp mirin 1 ½ Tbsp sake 1 ½ Tbsp soy sauce 1 ½ tsp sugar To serve
3 cups cooked Japanese short-grain rice small bunch mitsuba or green onion/scallion shichimi togarashi (optional for sprinkling) Instructions Gather all the ingredients. Combine dashi, mirin, sake, soy sauce in a bowl or a liquid measuring cup.</description></item><item><title>Pasta e fagioli</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/pasta-e-fagioli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/pasta-e-fagioli/</guid><description>Ingredients 70-90 g of macaroni or tubetti pasta 250 g boiled borlotti or cannellini beans (canned or dried, soaked, and boiled) 180 g of fresh tomatoes (canned tomatoes are also fine) 2 garlic cloves 3-4 tablespoons of extra virgin olive oil fresh parsley salt and pepper Instructions Sauté the peeled and slightly crushed garlic with the oil for 1 minute. Then add the fresh tomatoes cut into 4 parts with some chopped parsley.</description></item><item><title>Pea and ham soup</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/pea-and-ham-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/pea-and-ham-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 ham hock 500 g green split peas 1-2 onions, chopped 2-3 carrots, chopped 3-4 celery sticks, chopped 2 potatoes, chopped 2-3 bay leaves Garnish
parsley, finely chopped bread Instructions Place the ham hock in the pressure cooker and cover with water. Cook for 45 minutes on high with natural steam release. After the pressure is released, take out ham hock and shred or chop the meat.</description></item><item><title>Porridge</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/porridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/porridge/</guid><description>Ingredients ⅓ cup rolled oats ⅓ cup milk ⅔ cup water big pinch of salt toppings of your choice Instructions Put the oats in a saucepan along with the milk, water, and salt and bring slowly to the boil, stirring frequently with a wooden spoon. Turn down the heat even further, and simmer, stirring very regularly, for about 5-10 minutes, until you have the consistency you require. Cover and allow to sit for a few minutes, then serve with the toppings of your choice and a moat of cold milk.</description></item><item><title>Prawn and garlic pasta</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/prawn-and-garlic-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/prawn-and-garlic-pasta/</guid><description>Ingredients 250 g large prawns, peeled and split down the back, veins removed salt 4 tablespoons (60ml) extra-virgin olive oil, divided 5 medium cloves garlic, finely minced (about 2 tablespoons plus 2 teaspoons; 50g) large pinch red pepper flakes ½ cup (125ml) dry vermouth or white wine 3 tablespoons (40g) unsalted butter, cut into tablespoon-size pieces 1 tablespoons (15ml) fresh juice and 1 teaspoon grated zest from 1 lemon, divided 200g dried linguine or spaghetti 1 loosely packed cup (1/2 ounce; 15g) fresh parsley leaves and tender stems, finely minced Instructions In a large sauté pan, heat half the olive oil over high heat until shimmering.</description></item><item><title>Reverse braised beef</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/reverse-braised-beef/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/reverse-braised-beef/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 kg beef chuck or oyster blade 1 tbsp vinegar 1 tbsp sugar 1 tsp soy sauce oil salt pepper Instructions Place the meat in the pressure cooker. Pour in enough water to almost cover the meat, and cook on high pressure for 45 minutes with natural steam release. Gently fish the meat out of the pan, breaking it up as little as possible, and let the pieces dry/steam-off on paper towels for a few minutes.</description></item><item><title>Rice bowl</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/rice-bowl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/rice-bowl/</guid><description>Ingredients Steamed white rice Protein, e.g. boiled egg, Omelette, Spicy tuna with mayo, Chicken teriyaki Vegetables, e.g. julienne carrots, corn kernels, cherry tomatoes, Quick cucumber pickle, salad with sesame dressing Pickled ginger Rice seasoning Instructions Put the cooked rice in a bowl. Put the other ingredients on top.</description></item><item><title>Rich sugar syrup</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/rich-sugar-syrup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/rich-sugar-syrup/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cups sugar 1 cup water Instructions Combine in a saucepan. Heat while stirring until sugar is fully dissolved. Then turn off heat. Allow to cool and put in jar. Keep in the fridge. Notes This is a rich sugar syrup which is 2:1 sugar to water by volume. To convert cocktail recipes between simple syrup (1:1 by volume) and rich syrup (2:1 by volume) multiply by two-thirds (2/3 = 0.</description></item><item><title>Seafood spaghetti marinara</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/seafood-spaghetti-marinara/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/seafood-spaghetti-marinara/</guid><description>Ingredients 200 g dried spaghetti pasta (or other long pasta of choice) 2 ½ tbsp olive oil, separated 400 g seafood marinara mix 2 garlic cloves, minced ½ onion, finely chopped ½ cup white wine 2 cups tomato passata/tomato puree ½ tsp sugar 2 tbsp finely chopped fresh parsley Instructions Bring a large pot of salted water to boil. Cook pasta according to packet directions, but reduce the cooking time by 1 minute (because the pasta will finish cooking in the sauce).</description></item><item><title>Sichuan eggplants and green beans</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/sichuan-eggplants-and-green-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/sichuan-eggplants-and-green-beans/</guid><description>Ingredients 100 g green beans, trimmed and cut into halves 2 long eggplants cut into strips Pinch of salt 4 cloves garlic, minced 2 fresh chili peppers, or you can use dried red pepper 3 green onions 2 tablespoons light soy sauce 4 tablespoons cooking oil Instructions Prepare a large pot of water and add pinch of salt. Cut the eggplants into long strips and then throw the strips into the salty water.</description></item><item><title>Silken tofu with celery salad</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/silken-tofu-with-celery-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/silken-tofu-with-celery-salad/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 stalk celery, cut into thin 2-inch matchsticks 1/2 cup fresh cilantro leaves and tender stems 3 whole scallions, sliced into thin slicers at an acute bias 1/2 teaspoon toasted sichuan peppercorns 1/2 teaspoon toasted whole cumin seed 1 tablespoon sesame paste (such as tahini), or peanut butter 1 teaspoon soy sauce 2 teaspoons Chinkiang vinegar 2 teaspoons fermented chili broad bean paste 2 teaspoons sugar 1/4 cup Chinese roasted chili oil 1 medium clove garlic, finely minced (about 1 teaspoon) 600 g soft silken tofu 1 teaspoon toasted sesame seeds Instructions Combine celery, cilantro, and scallions in a medium bowl and cover with ice cold water.</description></item><item><title>Slow-roast lamb</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/slow-roast-lamb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/slow-roast-lamb/</guid><description>Ingredients 1.8kg lamb shoulder (bone in) 2 tbsp olive oil 2 tsp salt 1 tsp black pepper 1 onion, quartered (no need to peel) 1 head garlic, cut in half horizontally 3 garlic cloves, cut into slivers 8 sprigs rosemary 1 cup water Instructions Preheat oven to 240°C (220°C fan forced). Rub the lamb with the olive oil, salt and pepper. Use a thin, sharp knife to make 12 incisions in the lamb, deep as you can but without piercing through the bottom of the lamb.</description></item><item><title>Southern fried chicken</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/southern-fried-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/southern-fried-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons paprika 2 tablespoons freshly ground black pepper 2 teaspoons garlic powder 2 teaspoons dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1 cup buttermilk 1 large egg 1/4 tsp kosher salt One whole chicken, about 4 pounds, cut into 10 pieces or 3 1/2 pounds bone-in, skin-on breasts, legs, drumsticks, and/or wings 1 1/2 cups all purpose flour 1/2 cup cornstarch 1 teaspoon baking powder 4 cups vegetable shortening or peanut oil Instructions Combine the paprika, black pepper, garlic powder, oregano, and cayenne in a small bowl and mix thoroughly with a fork.</description></item><item><title>Spanakopita</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/spanakopita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/spanakopita/</guid><description>Ingredients 500 g frozen chopped spinach, thawed and well-drained 2 bunches flat-leaf parsley, stems trimmed, finely chopped 1 large yellow onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, minced 2 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 4 eggs 300 g feta cheese, crumbled 2 tsp dried dill weed Freshly-ground black pepper 1 package phyllo pastry 1 cup extra virgin olive oil, more if needed Instructions Preheat the oven to 180C. Before you begin mixing the filling, be sure the spinach is very well drained, and squeeze out any excess liquid by hand.</description></item><item><title>Stovetop espresso</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/stovetop-espresso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/stovetop-espresso/</guid><description>Ingredients 21 g coffee water Instructions Finely grind coffee. Add boiling water up to below the pressure release valve. Add coffee to basket but don&amp;rsquo;t tamp. Put on small stove burner. Allow to percolate but pull off when the stream turns from golden brown to pale yellow. Notes This should make about 100 ml of coffee.</description></item><item><title>Thịt nướng (Vietnamese grilled meat)</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/th%E1%BB%8Bt-n%C6%B0%E1%BB%9Bng-vietnamese-grilled-meat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/th%E1%BB%8Bt-n%C6%B0%E1%BB%9Bng-vietnamese-grilled-meat/</guid><description>Ingredients 1-1.5 kg pork butt or top sirloin, thinly sliced approximately 1/4 inch thick, or same weight in chicken thighs not sliced 3 shallots, finely minced 5 cloves garlic, finely minced 1/2 cup lemongrass, finely minced 3 tablespoons white sesame seeds 3 1/2 tablespoons sugar 1 tablespoon salt 1/2 tablespoon black pepper 1 teaspoon MSG (optional) 2 tablespoons honey 3 tablespoons fish sauce 1 tablespoon sesame oil 1/2 tablespoon vegetable oil Instructions Combine all ingredients from shallots through vegetable oil in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Vegetarian soy-milk ramen</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/vegetarian-soy-milk-ramen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/vegetarian-soy-milk-ramen/</guid><description>Ingredients Dashi
¾ cup water 1 piece kombu (dried kelp) (1&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot;, 2.5 cm x 5 cm) 1 dried shiitake mushroom Soup
1 Tbsp toasted white sesame seeds 2 cloves garlic ½ inch ginger green onion/scallion (use white part) 2 tsp sesame oil (roasted) 2 tsp doubanjiang (spicy chili bean paste) 2 tsp miso 1 Tbsp sake 2 tsp soy sauce 1 cup unsweetened soy milk ½ cup dashi ¼ tsp kosher/sea salt Dash white pepper powder Ramen</description></item><item><title>Wedding soup</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/wedding-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/wedding-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1 large leek, finely sliced 2 garlic cloves, minced 2 celery stalks, diced 2 bay leaves 2 litres chicken stock 150 g small pasta, such as orzo, acini di pepe 1 bunch greens, such as curly endive or kale (cavalo nero), roughly chopped lemon, to serve Meatballs
500 g mince, such as pork, chicken, or a mix ½ cup breadcrumbs, wetted with some milk 2 garlic cloves, minced 25-50 g grated parmesan ½ cup fresh chopped herbs, such as chives, parsley, sage ½ tsp dried oregano 1 egg salt and black pepper Instructions Preheat the oven to 200˚C.</description></item></channel></rss>