<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>basics on Recipes</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/collections/basics/</link><description>Recent content in basics on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/collections/basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black beans</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/black-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/black-beans/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 x 400g cans of black beans 1 onion, chopped 3-4 garlic cloves, minced 2 tsp cumin 2 tsp ancho chili 2 bay leaves salt coriander leaves Instructions Saute onion in oil in a saucepan on medium heat until softened. Add garlic and cook for a couple of minutes. Fry dried spices for a couple of minutes until fragrant. Rinse beans then add them to the pot and cover with water.</description></item><item><title>Chemex coffee</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/chemex-coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/chemex-coffee/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 g coffee 510 ml water Instructions Heat water to 91°C. Grind coffee beans on a coarse setting. Place filter the top of the Chemex, pre-soak with hot water, and discard the water. Place the grounds into the filter. Tare scale, start a timer, and circle pour 60 ml of water onto the grounds and bloom the coffee for 30 seconds. After the bloom, pour 50ml of water in a circular motion.</description></item><item><title>Chickpeas (pressure cooker)</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/chickpeas-pressure-cooker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/chickpeas-pressure-cooker/</guid><description>Ingredients 450 g dried chickpeas 6 cups water 1 teaspoon fine sea salt 1 small onion, peeled and halved 2 garlic cloves, peeled 2 bay leaves Instructions Check chickpeas for stones and dirt clods. Rinse the chickpeas, then put them in the pressure cooker. Add the water, onion, garlic, and bay leaves. Cook on high pressure for 45 minutes with a natural steam release. Notes Recipe derived from Mike Vrobel at Dad Cooks Dinner.</description></item><item><title>Porridge</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/porridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/porridge/</guid><description>Ingredients ⅓ cup rolled oats ⅓ cup milk ⅔ cup water big pinch of salt toppings of your choice Instructions Put the oats in a saucepan along with the milk, water, and salt and bring slowly to the boil, stirring frequently with a wooden spoon. Turn down the heat even further, and simmer, stirring very regularly, for about 5-10 minutes, until you have the consistency you require. Cover and allow to sit for a few minutes, then serve with the toppings of your choice and a moat of cold milk.</description></item><item><title>Rich sugar syrup</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/rich-sugar-syrup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/rich-sugar-syrup/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cups sugar 1 cup water Instructions Combine in a saucepan. Heat while stirring until sugar is fully dissolved. Then turn off heat. Allow to cool and put in jar. Keep in the fridge. Notes This is a rich sugar syrup which is 2:1 sugar to water by volume. To convert cocktail recipes between simple syrup (1:1 by volume) and rich syrup (2:1 by volume) multiply by two-thirds (2/3 = 0.</description></item><item><title>Stovetop espresso</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/stovetop-espresso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/stovetop-espresso/</guid><description>Ingredients 21 g coffee water Instructions Finely grind coffee. Add boiling water up to below the pressure release valve. Add coffee to basket but don&amp;rsquo;t tamp. Put on small stove burner. Allow to percolate but pull off when the stream turns from golden brown to pale yellow. Notes This should make about 100 ml of coffee.</description></item></channel></rss>