<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>basics on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/basics/</link><description>Recent content in basics on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black beans</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/black-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/black-beans/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 x 400g cans of black beans 1 onion, chopped 3-4 garlic cloves, minced 2 tsp cumin 2 tsp ancho chili 2 bay leaves salt coriander leaves Instructions Saute onion in oil in a saucepan on medium heat until softened. Add garlic and cook for a couple of minutes. Fry dried spices for a couple of minutes until fragrant. Rinse beans then add them to the pot and cover with water.</description></item><item><title>Chickpeas (pressure cooker)</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/chickpeas-pressure-cooker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/chickpeas-pressure-cooker/</guid><description>Ingredients 450 g dried chickpeas 6 cups water 1 teaspoon fine sea salt 1 small onion, peeled and halved 2 garlic cloves, peeled 2 bay leaves Instructions Check chickpeas for stones and dirt clods. Rinse the chickpeas, then put them in the pressure cooker. Add the water, onion, garlic, and bay leaves. Cook on high pressure for 45 minutes with a natural steam release. Notes Recipe derived from Mike Vrobel at Dad Cooks Dinner.</description></item><item><title>Pan-fried Brussels sprouts</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/pan-fried-brussels-sprouts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/pan-fried-brussels-sprouts/</guid><description>Ingredients about 500 g Brussels sprouts 2 tbsp olive oil stock cube salt and pepper Instructions Heat frying pan over medium high heat and add olive oil. Add sprouts cut side facing down and cook until nicely browned, about 5 minutes. Turn over and cook the other side until a bit browned. Add about 1/3 a cup of water to the pan and a stock cube (crumbled), and put the lid on.</description></item><item><title>Porridge</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/porridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/porridge/</guid><description>Ingredients ⅓ cup rolled oats ⅓ cup milk ⅔ cup water big pinch of salt toppings of your choice Instructions Put the oats in a saucepan along with the milk, water, and salt and bring slowly to the boil, stirring frequently with a wooden spoon. Turn down the heat even further, and simmer, stirring very regularly, for about 5-10 minutes, until you have the consistency you require. Cover and allow to sit for a few minutes, then serve with the toppings of your choice and a moat of cold milk.</description></item><item><title>Rich sugar syrup</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/rich-sugar-syrup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/rich-sugar-syrup/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cups sugar 1 cup water Instructions Combine in a saucepan. Heat while stirring until sugar is fully dissolved. Then turn off heat. Allow to cool and put in jar. Keep in the fridge. Notes This is a rich sugar syrup which is 2:1 sugar to water by volume. To convert cocktail recipes between simple syrup (1:1 by volume) and rich syrup (2:1 by volume) multiply by two-thirds (2/3 = 0.</description></item></channel></rss>