<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>stew on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/stew/</link><description>Recent content in stew on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022-2024, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/stew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beef cheek stew</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/beef-cheek-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/beef-cheek-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 3kg beef cheeks 100ml olive oil 2 brown onions, chopped 1 whole head of garlic, split 2 carrots, chopped 1/4 bunch thyme 3 fresh bay leaves 1 cinnamon stick 2 star anise 1lt Pedro Ximenez sherry 500ml red wine Instructions In a heavy-based pot, heat olive oil, season beef cheeks with salt and pepper, and brown well. Remove from the pan. Add onion, garlic head and carrots to caramelise.</description></item><item><title>Chilli con carne</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/chilli-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/chilli-con-carne/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tbsp olive oil 3 garlic cloves, minced 1 onion, diced 1 red capsicum, diced 500 g beef mince 3 tbsp tomato paste 800 g can crushed tomato 420 g can red kidney beans 2 beef stock cubes 1 1/2 tsp sugar 125 - 375 ml water Salt and pepper Spice mix
1 - 2 tsp cayenne pepper (adjust to taste) 4 tsp paprika powder 5 tsp cumin powder 2 tsp garlic powder (or onion powder) 2 tsp onion powder 2 tsp oregano To serve</description></item><item><title>Chilli con veggie</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/chilli-con-veggie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/chilli-con-veggie/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 medium onions 4 cloves of garlic 1 medium leek 1 long fresh red chilli 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 tablespoons ground cumin 2 tablespoons ground coriander 2 tablespoons smoked paprika ½ a cinnamon stick, or 1 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2 tablespoons dried oregano 1 whole nutmeg , for grating 2 tablespoons tomato purée 250 g dried green lentils 250 g dried red lentils 2 x 400 g tins of red kidney beans 2 x 400 g tins of black beans 2 x 400 g tins of chopped tomatoes 1.</description></item><item><title>Lamb, chickpea and dried fruit stew</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/lamb-chickpea-and-dried-fruit-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/lamb-chickpea-and-dried-fruit-stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons oil or butter 800 g lamb stew meat (shoulder, leg or shank) cut onto 1 ½ inch cubes 1 onion, diced 5 garlic cloves, rough chopped 1 teaspoon of each: salt, pepper, cumin, coriander, turmeric, cinnamon, and cumin seeds (seeds are optional, add another teaspoon ground cumin if no seeds) ½ teaspoon chilli flakes (Aleppo chilli flakes are nice) and more for garnish 2 tablespoons tomato paste ¼ cup apple cider vinegar (or red wine vinegar) 2 tablespoons honey or brown sugar 1 1/4 cups chicken stock or broth 1 x 400 g can chickpeas, rinsed and drained ¼ cup raisins or dried apricots (chopped), or even dried currants A few bay leaves, and thyme and rosemary sprigs 1-2 teaspoons butter 1-2 teaspoons flour Instructions Brown the meat in cast iron pan.</description></item><item><title>Pasta e fagioli</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/pasta-e-fagioli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/pasta-e-fagioli/</guid><description>Ingredients 70-90 g of macaroni or tubetti pasta 250 g boiled borlotti or cannellini beans (canned or dried, soaked, and boiled) 180 g of fresh tomatoes (canned tomatoes are also fine) 2 garlic cloves 3-4 tablespoons of extra virgin olive oil fresh parsley salt and pepper Instructions Sauté the peeled and slightly crushed garlic with the oil for 1 minute. Then add the fresh tomatoes cut into 4 parts with some chopped parsley.</description></item></channel></rss>