<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>italian on Recipes</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/cuisines/italian/</link><description>Recent content in italian on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/cuisines/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Broccoli pasta</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/broccoli-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/broccoli-pasta/</guid><description>Ingredients 200 g short pasta 1 broccoli, cut into small florets ½-1 cup grated parmesan zest of 1 lemon about 2 tbsp lemon juice 5 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 2 garlic cloves, minced ½ tsp chili flakes salt and pepper extra parmesan Instructions Add pasta to boiling salted water. While pasta is cooking, fry off garlic and chili flakes in the oil for a minute or so until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Cannellini, potato, and spinach soup</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/cannellini-potato-and-spinach-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/cannellini-potato-and-spinach-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 cans cannellini or other white beans 2 large potato, diced 1 small onion, chopped 2 garlic cloves 2 cups water 1 stock cube 2 cups baby spinach 1 handful Italian flat parsley, chopped 2 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1/4 tsp chilli flakes 1/2 tsp salt Instructions Rinse your beans under runny water and drain, you want to remove the cloudy water. In a large pot heat gently 1 Tbsp of extra virgin olive oil and add 1 chopped garlic clove (keep the other one for the dressing), onion, chilli and cook for about 3 minutes or until the onion starts to soften.</description></item><item><title>Chicken and mushroom risotto</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/chicken-and-mushroom-risotto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/chicken-and-mushroom-risotto/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tbsp olive oil 400 g chicken thigh fillets 400 g mushrooms, sliced 2 tbsp / 30 g butter 2 garlic cloves, minced 1 onion, finely diced ½ cup / 125 ml white wine 250 g arborio risotto rice 1 L chicken stock 35 g freshly grated parmesan cheese 25-50 g butter parsley, chopped Instructions Heat oil in a wide pot or skillet over high heat, cook chicken thighs, then set aside.</description></item><item><title>Melanzane alla Parmigiana (eggplant Parmesan)</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/melanzane-alla-parmigiana-eggplant-parmesan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/melanzane-alla-parmigiana-eggplant-parmesan/</guid><description>Ingredients Olive oil, vegetable oil, or a combination, for frying 1 kg eggplant, sliced 1/4 inch thick Salt 1 1/4 cups (360ml) tomato sauce (see note) 3/4 pound shredded fresh mozzarella (12 ounces; 340g) Torn fresh oregano leaves, from about 4 sprigs Instructions Preheat oven to 200°C. Fill a large cast iron skillet with 1/2 inch oil and heat over high heat until shimmering. Working in batches, fry eggplant slices, turning, until browned on both sides, about 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Pasta e fagioli</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/pasta-e-fagioli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/pasta-e-fagioli/</guid><description>Ingredients 70-90 g of macaroni or tubetti pasta 250 g boiled borlotti or cannellini beans (canned or dried, soaked, and boiled) 180 g of fresh tomatoes (canned tomatoes are also fine) 2 garlic cloves 3-4 tablespoons of extra virgin olive oil fresh parsley salt and pepper Instructions Sauté the peeled and slightly crushed garlic with the oil for 1 minute. Then add the fresh tomatoes cut into 4 parts with some chopped parsley.</description></item><item><title>Prawn and garlic pasta</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/prawn-and-garlic-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/prawn-and-garlic-pasta/</guid><description>Ingredients 250 g large prawns, peeled and split down the back, veins removed salt 4 tablespoons (60ml) extra-virgin olive oil, divided 5 medium cloves garlic, finely minced (about 2 tablespoons plus 2 teaspoons; 50g) large pinch red pepper flakes ½ cup (125ml) dry vermouth or white wine 3 tablespoons (40g) unsalted butter, cut into tablespoon-size pieces 1 tablespoons (15ml) fresh juice and 1 teaspoon grated zest from 1 lemon, divided 200g dried linguine or spaghetti 1 loosely packed cup (1/2 ounce; 15g) fresh parsley leaves and tender stems, finely minced Instructions In a large sauté pan, heat half the olive oil over high heat until shimmering.</description></item><item><title>Seafood spaghetti marinara</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/seafood-spaghetti-marinara/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/seafood-spaghetti-marinara/</guid><description>Ingredients 200 g dried spaghetti pasta (or other long pasta of choice) 2 ½ tbsp olive oil, separated 400 g seafood marinara mix 2 garlic cloves, minced ½ onion, finely chopped ½ cup white wine 2 cups tomato passata/tomato puree ½ tsp sugar 2 tbsp finely chopped fresh parsley Instructions Bring a large pot of salted water to boil. Cook pasta according to packet directions, but reduce the cooking time by 1 minute (because the pasta will finish cooking in the sauce).</description></item></channel></rss>