<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fried on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/fried/</link><description>Recent content in fried on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/collections/fried/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baja fish tacos</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/baja-fish-tacos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/baja-fish-tacos/</guid><description>Ingredients Cabbage slaw
5 cups (or one 10-ounce bag) shredded red cabbage 3 tablespoons minced red onion 1/2 cup fresh chopped cilantro 3 tablespoons cider vinegar 1-1/2 teaspoons vegetable oil 1/2 teaspoon salt Chipotle sauce
3/4 cup mayonnaise, best quality such as Hellmann&amp;rsquo;s 2 tablespoons lime juice, from one lime 2-3 chipotle chiles in adobo sauce (canned), roughly chopped, plus 1-2 teaspoons sauce (see note below) 1 large garlic clove, roughly chopped Beer batter</description></item><item><title>Falafel</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/falafel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/falafel/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 pound dried chickpeas (1 generous cup; 225g) 2 ounces picked fresh cilantro, parsley, or mint leaves, or preferably a mixture of all three (about 2 cups; 55g) 6 scallions, white and pale green parts only, sliced (about 2 ounces; 55g) 2 medium cloves garlic, minced (about 2 teaspoons; 10ml) 1 teaspoon (about 4g) ground cumin 1/2 teaspoon (about 2g) ground coriander seed 2 teaspoons (about 10g) kosher salt, plus more for seasoning 2 to 3 cups (480 to 720ml) vegetable oil, for frying Tahini sauce and hummus for serving Instructions Rinse chickpeas and place in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Karaage</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/karaage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/karaage/</guid><description>Ingredients 600g chicken thighs, skin-on 3 tbsp light soy sauce 2 tbsp sake 1 tbsp grated ginger, juice only ½ tsp sugar ¾ cup potato flour (or substitute cornflour) about 2L canola, sunflower or other vegetable oil, for deep frying Japanese mayonnaise, to serve lemon slices, to serve shichimi togarashi (Japanese seven-spice), to serve (optional) Instructions Cut the chicken into 5cm pieces. Combine the chicken with the soy sauce, sake, ginger juice and sugar and stand for 10 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Southern fried chicken</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/southern-fried-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/southern-fried-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons paprika 2 tablespoons freshly ground black pepper 2 teaspoons garlic powder 2 teaspoons dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1 cup buttermilk 1 large egg 1/4 tsp kosher salt One whole chicken, about 4 pounds, cut into 10 pieces or 3 1/2 pounds bone-in, skin-on breasts, legs, drumsticks, and/or wings 1 1/2 cups all purpose flour 1/2 cup cornstarch 1 teaspoon baking powder 4 cups vegetable shortening or peanut oil Instructions Combine the paprika, black pepper, garlic powder, oregano, and cayenne in a small bowl and mix thoroughly with a fork.</description></item></channel></rss>