<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fish on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/ingredients/fish/</link><description>Recent content in fish on Recipes collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/ingredients/fish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baja fish tacos</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/baja-fish-tacos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/baja-fish-tacos/</guid><description>Ingredients Cabbage slaw
5 cups (or one 10-ounce bag) shredded red cabbage 3 tablespoons minced red onion 1/2 cup fresh chopped cilantro 3 tablespoons cider vinegar 1-1/2 teaspoons vegetable oil 1/2 teaspoon salt Chipotle sauce
3/4 cup mayonnaise, best quality such as Hellmann&amp;rsquo;s 2 tablespoons lime juice, from one lime 2-3 chipotle chiles in adobo sauce (canned), roughly chopped, plus 1-2 teaspoons sauce (see note below) 1 large garlic clove, roughly chopped Beer batter</description></item><item><title>Fish potato cakes</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/fish-potato-cakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/fish-potato-cakes/</guid><description>Ingredients 700 g potatoes, peeled and chopped 500 g salmon (or white fish) fillets ½ cup flat-leaf parsley leaves, finely chopped 1 tablespoon dill, finely chopped 1 tablespoon Dijon mustard, plus extra to serve 1 egg, lightly beaten 1 teaspoon finely grated lemon rind sea salt and cracked black pepper 2 cups (140g) panko breadcrumbs vegetable oil, for shallow-frying Instructions Boil potatoes in salted water until tender. Drain well, place in a large bowl and mash.</description></item><item><title>Mas riha (Maldivian fish curry)</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/mas-riha-maldivian-fish-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/mas-riha-maldivian-fish-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tbsp coconut oil 4 cloves garlic, minced 2 cardamom pods 1″ fresh ginger, peeled and sliced into matchsticks 10 curry leaves (1 tsp curry powder okay) 1 jalapeño or other green chile (serrano, etc), stem, seeds, and ribs removed, sliced 1 onion, sliced 1/2 tsp each ground fennel, cumin, turmeric, black pepper 1 can coconut milk (14 oz) 1 cinnamon stick salt to taste (about 1 tsp) 1 lb fresh tuna or other firm fish (mahi mahi, swordfish, etc), cut into cubes and lightly salted Instructions Lightly salt the fish and set it aside.</description></item></channel></rss>