<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sugar-syrup on Recipes</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/tags/sugar-syrup/</link><description>Recent content in sugar-syrup on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/tags/sugar-syrup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aviation</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/aviation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/aviation/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml Gin 20 ml Lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml Sugar syrup 5ml crème de violette cherry Instructions Shake ingredients (crème de violette optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with cherry.</description></item><item><title>Caipirinha</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/caipirinha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/caipirinha/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Cachaça 1/2 Lime 15 ml Sugar syrup Instructions Muddle quartered lime and syrup in a rocks glass. Add ice and cachaça and stir.</description></item><item><title>Daiquiri</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/daiquiri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/daiquiri/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Rum 20 ml Lime juice 10 ml Sugar syrup lime zest lime slice Instructions Shake ingredients including lime zest. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Hemingway special</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/hemingway-special/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/hemingway-special/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Rum 30 ml Grapefruit juice 15 ml Lime juice 15 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml Sugar syrup lime slice Instructions Shake with ice. Serve in a cocktail glass Garnish with lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Mojito</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/mojito/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/mojito/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Rum 20 ml Lime juice 20 ml Sugar syrup a few Mint leaves Soda water mint sprig Instructions Crush ice in clean tea towel. Lightly clap mint. Add ingredients except soda to highball glass. Add crushed ice and stir briefly, and top with soda water. Garnish with a mint sprig.</description></item><item><title>Old fashioned</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/old-fashioned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/old-fashioned/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Rye whisky or Bourbon 5 ml Sugar syrup 4 dashes Aromatic bitters orange or lemon twist Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in a rocks glass over ice. Garnish with a twist.</description></item><item><title>Pisco sour</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/pisco-sour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/pisco-sour/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml Pisco 30 ml Lime juice 15 ml Sugar syrup 1/2 Egg white Aromatic bitters lime slice Instructions Dry shake ingredients. Then shake with ice. Serve in a rocks glass without ice. Garnish with drops of bitters and a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Sazerac</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/sazerac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/sazerac/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Rye whisky 5 ml Sugar syrup 4 dashes Creole bitters 4 dashes Absinthe lemon twist Instructions (Optional) rinse glass with absinthe. Stirred. Serve in a rocks glass without ice. Garnish with a lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Southside</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/southside/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/southside/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Gin 30 ml Lime juice 15 ml Sugar syrup 1 Mint sprig 1 mint leaf Instructions Shaken (without mint). Rolled (with mint). Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with mint leaf.</description></item><item><title>Tom Collins</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/tom-collins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/tom-collins/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Gin 30 ml Lemon juice 15 ml Sugar syrup Soda water lemon slice Instructions Add ingredients except soda to highball glass and stir to combine. Add soda water to halfway up glass. Fill glass with ice. Garnish with lemon slice.</description></item><item><title>Whiskey sour</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/whiskey-sour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/drink/whiskey-sour/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Bourbon 30 ml Lemon juice 15 ml Sugar syrup 4 dashes Orange bitters 1/2 Egg white (optional) cherry orange twist Instructions Dry shake ingredients. Then shake with ice and double strain. Serve in a rocks glass over fresh ice. Garnish with orange twist and cherry.</description></item></channel></rss>