<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>south-asian on Recipes</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/cuisines/south-asian/</link><description>Recent content in south-asian on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/cuisines/south-asian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bengali rice porridge with lentils and chicken</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/bengali-rice-porridge-with-lentils-and-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/bengali-rice-porridge-with-lentils-and-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 3/4 cup jasmine rice 1 inch fresh turmeric or 1 teaspoon dried turmeric 1 inch fresh ginger 2 tablespoons butter or ghee 1/2 teaspoon Kashmiri red chilli powder 1/4 cup red lentils 6 cups (1.5 L) chicken stock 2 medium potato, peeled, 1 cm dice 400 g chicken thighs Coriander chutney
1/2 bunch coriander, finely chopped 2 Thai green chiles, finely chopped 2 tablespoons (30 mL) lime juice 2 tablespoons (30 mL) olive oil To serve</description></item><item><title>Chickpea coconut curry</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/chickpea-coconut-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/chickpea-coconut-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients ¼ cup oil 4 garlic cloves, chopped 1 large yellow onion, chopped 1 (2-inch) piece ginger, finely chopped Kosher salt and black pepper 1 teaspoons ground turmeric 1 teaspoon red-pepper flakes 3 (400 g) cans chickpeas, drained and rinsed 2 (400 g) cans full-fat coconut milk 2 cups vegetable or chicken stock or water 1 bunch Swiss chard, kale or collard greens, stems removed, torn into bite-size pieces 1 cup mint leaves, for serving Toasted pita, lavash or other flatbread, for serving (optional) Instructions Heat oil in a large pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Mas riha (Maldivian fish curry)</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/mas-riha-maldivian-fish-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/eat/mas-riha-maldivian-fish-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tbsp coconut oil 4 cloves garlic, minced 2 cardamom pods 1″ fresh ginger, peeled and sliced into matchsticks 10 curry leaves (1 tsp curry powder okay) 1 jalapeño or other green chile (serrano, etc), stem, seeds, and ribs removed, sliced 1 onion, sliced 1/2 tsp each ground fennel, cumin, turmeric, black pepper 1 can coconut milk (14 oz) 1 cinnamon stick salt to taste (about 1 tsp) 1 lb fresh tuna or other firm fish (mahi mahi, swordfish, etc), cut into cubes and lightly salted Instructions Lightly salt the fish and set it aside.</description></item></channel></rss>