<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>baked on Recipes</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/collections/baked/</link><description>Recent content in baked on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/collections/baked/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Melanzane alla Parmigiana (eggplant Parmesan)</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/melanzane-alla-parmigiana-eggplant-parmesan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/melanzane-alla-parmigiana-eggplant-parmesan/</guid><description>Ingredients Olive oil, vegetable oil, or a combination, for frying 1 kg eggplant, sliced 1/4 inch thick Salt 1 1/4 cups (360ml) tomato sauce (see note) 3/4 pound shredded fresh mozzarella (12 ounces; 340g) Torn fresh oregano leaves, from about 4 sprigs Instructions Preheat oven to 200°C. Fill a large cast iron skillet with 1/2 inch oil and heat over high heat until shimmering. Working in batches, fry eggplant slices, turning, until browned on both sides, about 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Mushroom and sausage pasta bake</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/mushroom-and-sausage-pasta-bake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/mushroom-and-sausage-pasta-bake/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup Panko-style bread crumbs 6 ounces grated Parmesan cheese 1/4 cup chopped fresh parsley leaves 2 tablespoons finely minced fresh chives 2 small shallots, finely minced (about 1/2 cup) 2 medium cloves garlic, minced (about 2 teaspoons) 2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper 2 tablespoons unsalted butter 8 ounces Italian sausage (mild or hot), removed from casings 1 pound mixed mushrooms (such as portobello, shiitake, and oyster), cleaned and thinly sliced 1 tablespoon soy sauce 1 tablespoon juice from 1 lemon 2 1/2 tablespoons all-purpose flour 2 cups homemade or store-bought low-sodium chicken stock 1 cup heavy cream 12 ounces fresh or 8 ounces dried ridged pasta such as rotini or campanelle Instructions Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and keep at a bare simmer.</description></item><item><title>Spanakopita</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/spanakopita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/spanakopita/</guid><description>Ingredients 500 g frozen chopped spinach, thawed and well-drained 2 bunches flat-leaf parsley, stems trimmed, finely chopped 1 large yellow onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, minced 2 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 4 eggs 300 g feta cheese, crumbled 2 tsp dried dill weed Freshly-ground black pepper 1 package phyllo pastry 1 cup extra virgin olive oil, more if needed Instructions Preheat the oven to 180C. Before you begin mixing the filling, be sure the spinach is very well drained, and squeeze out any excess liquid by hand.</description></item></channel></rss>