<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vegetarian on Recipes</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/collections/vegetarian/</link><description>Recent content in vegetarian on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/collections/vegetarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black bean burgers</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/black-bean-burgers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/black-bean-burgers/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 (15-ounce) cans black beans, rinsed and drained 4 tablespoons vegetable oil, divided 1 medium onion, finely chopped (about 1 cup) 1 large poblano pepper, finely chopped (about 1 cup) 3 medium cloves garlic, minced 1 chipotle chile in adobo sauce, finely chopped, plus 1 teaspoon sauce 3/4 cup roasted cashews 1/2 cup finely crumbled feta or cotija cheese 2 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 whole egg 3/4 cup panko bread crumbs Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper Cheese as desired, such as pepper jack, cheddar, muenster, or Swiss (optional) 6 to 8 hearty hamburger buns, toasted Condiments as desired, such as Chipotle Mayonnaise, ketchup, mustard, or mayonnaise (optional) Toppings as desired, such as shredded lettuce, sliced onions, and pickles (optional) Instructions Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat oven to 350°F.</description></item><item><title>Broccoli pasta</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/broccoli-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/broccoli-pasta/</guid><description>Ingredients 200 g short pasta 1 broccoli, cut into small florets ½-1 cup grated parmesan zest of 1 lemon about 2 tbsp lemon juice 5 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 2 garlic cloves, minced ½ tsp chili flakes salt and pepper extra parmesan Instructions Add pasta to boiling salted water. While pasta is cooking, fry off garlic and chili flakes in the oil for a minute or so until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Cannellini, potato, and spinach soup</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/cannellini-potato-and-spinach-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/cannellini-potato-and-spinach-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 cans cannellini or other white beans 2 large potato, diced 1 small onion, chopped 2 garlic cloves 2 cups water 1 stock cube 2 cups baby spinach 1 handful Italian flat parsley, chopped 2 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1/4 tsp chilli flakes 1/2 tsp salt Instructions Rinse your beans under runny water and drain, you want to remove the cloudy water. In a large pot heat gently 1 Tbsp of extra virgin olive oil and add 1 chopped garlic clove (keep the other one for the dressing), onion, chilli and cook for about 3 minutes or until the onion starts to soften.</description></item><item><title>Cauliflower puree</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/cauliflower-puree/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/cauliflower-puree/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 medium cauliflower head 50g butter 185ml thickened cream Instructions Chop cauliflower florets off central stalk, discard stalk then slice florets finely. Heat butter and cream in a heavy-based pot, add cauliflower, mix well and cover with a lid. Simmer for about 35 minutes or until soft. Puree until smooth and check seasoning. Store with baking paper on top to stop a skin forming. Notes Recipe derived from Good Food.</description></item><item><title>Channa masala</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/channa-masala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/channa-masala/</guid><description>Ingredients 4 medium cloves garlic, roughly chopped 1 (1-inch) knob ginger, peeled, roughly chopped 1 to 6 green Thai chiles (to taste), roughly chopped 2 tablespoons (30ml) juice from 1 lemon, divided Kosher salt 2 tablespoons (30ml) vegetable oil or ghee 2 teaspoons (8g) black mustard seed 1 teaspoon (4g) whole cumin seed 1 large onion, finely diced (about 1 1/2 cups; 300g) 2 teaspoons (8g) ground coriander 1/2 teaspoon (2g) freshly ground black pepper 1/2 teaspoon (2g) ground turmeric 1 1/2 teaspoons (6g) store-bought or homemade garam masala, divided 1 (14-ounce) can whole peeled tomatoes 2 (14-ounce) cans chickpeas, drained and rinsed 1 cup cilantro leaves, roughly chopped (1 ounce; 25g) Instructions Combine garlic, ginger, chiles, 1 tablespoon lemon juice, and 1/2 teaspoon kosher salt in a mortar and pestle or in the small work bowl of a food processor and pound or process until a fine paste is produced.</description></item><item><title>Chickpea coconut curry</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/chickpea-coconut-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/chickpea-coconut-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients ¼ cup oil 4 garlic cloves, chopped 1 large yellow onion, chopped 1 (2-inch) piece ginger, finely chopped Kosher salt and black pepper 1 teaspoons ground turmeric 1 teaspoon red-pepper flakes 3 (400 g) cans chickpeas, drained and rinsed 2 (400 g) cans full-fat coconut milk 2 cups vegetable or chicken stock or water 1 bunch Swiss chard, kale or collard greens, stems removed, torn into bite-size pieces 1 cup mint leaves, for serving Toasted pita, lavash or other flatbread, for serving (optional) Instructions Heat oil in a large pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Chilli con veggie</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/chilli-con-veggie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/chilli-con-veggie/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 medium onions 4 cloves of garlic 1 medium leek 1 long fresh red chilli 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 tablespoons ground cumin 2 tablespoons ground coriander 2 tablespoons smoked paprika ½ a cinnamon stick, or 1 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2 tablespoons dried oregano 1 whole nutmeg , for grating 2 tablespoons tomato purée 250 g dried green lentils 250 g dried red lentils 2 x 400 g tins of red kidney beans 2 x 400 g tins of black beans 2 x 400 g tins of chopped tomatoes 1.</description></item><item><title>Falafel</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/falafel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/falafel/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 pound dried chickpeas (1 generous cup; 225g) 2 ounces picked fresh cilantro, parsley, or mint leaves, or preferably a mixture of all three (about 2 cups; 55g) 6 scallions, white and pale green parts only, sliced (about 2 ounces; 55g) 2 medium cloves garlic, minced (about 2 teaspoons; 10ml) 1 teaspoon (about 4g) ground cumin 1/2 teaspoon (about 2g) ground coriander seed 2 teaspoons (about 10g) kosher salt, plus more for seasoning 2 to 3 cups (480 to 720ml) vegetable oil, for frying Tahini sauce and Hummus for serving Instructions Rinse chickpeas and place in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Fried cauliflower</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/fried-cauliflower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/fried-cauliflower/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 L peanut oil 1/2 cup cornstarch 1/2 cup all purpose flour 1/2 teaspoon baking powder Kosher salt 1/2 cup water 1/2 cup vodka 1 head cauliflower, cut into 1-inch florets 1/3 cup hot sauce, such as Frank&amp;rsquo;s 1 medium clove garlic, minced 1/4 cup picked celery leaves (optional) Instructions Preheat oil to 350°F in a large wok, Dutch oven, or deep fryer. Combine cornstarch, flour, baking powder, and 2 teaspoons kosher salt in a large bowl and whisk until homogeneous.</description></item><item><title>Melanzane alla Parmigiana (eggplant Parmesan)</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/melanzane-alla-parmigiana-eggplant-parmesan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/melanzane-alla-parmigiana-eggplant-parmesan/</guid><description>Ingredients Olive oil, vegetable oil, or a combination, for frying 1 kg eggplant, sliced 1/4 inch thick Salt 1 1/4 cups (360ml) tomato sauce (see note) 3/4 pound shredded fresh mozzarella (12 ounces; 340g) Torn fresh oregano leaves, from about 4 sprigs Instructions Preheat oven to 200°C. Fill a large cast iron skillet with 1/2 inch oil and heat over high heat until shimmering. Working in batches, fry eggplant slices, turning, until browned on both sides, about 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Pasta e fagioli</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/pasta-e-fagioli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/pasta-e-fagioli/</guid><description>Ingredients 70-90 g of macaroni or tubetti pasta 250 g boiled borlotti or cannellini beans (canned or dried, soaked, and boiled) 180 g of fresh tomatoes (canned tomatoes are also fine) 2 garlic cloves 3-4 tablespoons of extra virgin olive oil fresh parsley salt and pepper Instructions Sauté the peeled and slightly crushed garlic with the oil for 1 minute. Then add the fresh tomatoes cut into 4 parts with some chopped parsley.</description></item><item><title>Sichuan eggplants and green beans</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/sichuan-eggplants-and-green-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/sichuan-eggplants-and-green-beans/</guid><description>Ingredients 100 g green beans, trimmed and cut into halves 2 long eggplants cut into strips Pinch of salt 4 cloves garlic, minced 2 fresh chili peppers, or you can use dried red pepper 3 green onions 2 tablespoons light soy sauce 4 tablespoons cooking oil Instructions Prepare a large pot of water and add pinch of salt. Cut the eggplants into long strips and then throw the strips into the salty water.</description></item><item><title>Spanakopita</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/spanakopita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/spanakopita/</guid><description>Ingredients 500 g frozen chopped spinach, thawed and well-drained 2 bunches flat-leaf parsley, stems trimmed, finely chopped 1 large yellow onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, minced 2 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 4 eggs 300 g feta cheese, crumbled 2 tsp dried dill weed Freshly-ground black pepper 1 package phyllo pastry 1 cup extra virgin olive oil, more if needed Instructions Preheat the oven to 180C. Before you begin mixing the filling, be sure the spinach is very well drained, and squeeze out any excess liquid by hand.</description></item><item><title>Vegetarian soy-milk ramen</title><link>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/vegetarian-soy-milk-ramen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dmentipl.github.io/recipes/vegetarian-soy-milk-ramen/</guid><description>Ingredients Dashi
¾ cup water 1 piece kombu (dried kelp) (1&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot;, 2.5 cm x 5 cm) 1 dried shiitake mushroom Soup
1 Tbsp toasted white sesame seeds 2 cloves garlic ½ inch ginger green onion/scallion (use white part) 2 tsp sesame oil (roasted) 2 tsp doubanjiang (spicy chili bean paste) 2 tsp miso 1 Tbsp sake 2 tsp soy sauce 1 cup unsweetened soy milk ½ cup dashi ¼ tsp kosher/sea salt Dash white pepper powder Ramen</description></item></channel></rss>