<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>north-american on Recipes</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/cuisines/north-american/</link><description>Recent content in north-american on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/cuisines/north-american/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black bean burgers</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/black-bean-burgers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/black-bean-burgers/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 (15-ounce) cans black beans, rinsed and drained 4 tablespoons vegetable oil, divided 1 medium onion, finely chopped (about 1 cup) 1 large poblano pepper, finely chopped (about 1 cup) 3 medium cloves garlic, minced 1 chipotle chile in adobo sauce, finely chopped, plus 1 teaspoon sauce 3/4 cup roasted cashews 1/2 cup finely crumbled feta or cotija cheese 2 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 whole egg 3/4 cup panko bread crumbs Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper Cheese as desired, such as pepper jack, cheddar, muenster, or Swiss (optional) 6 to 8 hearty hamburger buns, toasted Condiments as desired, such as chipotle mayonnaise, ketchup, mustard, or mayonnaise (optional) Toppings as desired, such as shredded lettuce, sliced onions, and pickles (optional) Instructions Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat oven to 350°F.</description></item><item><title>Chilli con carne</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chilli-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chilli-con-carne/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tbsp olive oil 3 garlic cloves, minced 1 onion, diced 1 red capsicum, diced 500 g beef mince 3 tbsp tomato paste 800 g can crushed tomato 420 g can red kidney beans 2 beef stock cubes 1 1/2 tsp sugar 125 - 375 ml water Salt and pepper Spice mix
1 - 2 tsp cayenne pepper (adjust to taste) 4 tsp paprika powder 5 tsp cumin powder 2 tsp garlic powder (or onion powder) 2 tsp onion powder 2 tsp oregano To serve</description></item><item><title>Chilli con veggie</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chilli-con-veggie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/chilli-con-veggie/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 medium onions 4 cloves of garlic 1 medium leek 1 long fresh red chilli 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 tablespoons ground cumin 2 tablespoons ground coriander 2 tablespoons smoked paprika ½ a cinnamon stick, or 1 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2 tablespoons dried oregano 1 whole nutmeg , for grating 2 tablespoons tomato purée 250 g dried green lentils 250 g dried red lentils 2 x 400 g tins of red kidney beans 2 x 400 g tins of black beans 2 x 400 g tins of chopped tomatoes 1.</description></item><item><title>Fried cauliflower</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/fried-cauliflower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/fried-cauliflower/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 L peanut oil 1/2 cup cornstarch 1/2 cup all purpose flour 1/2 teaspoon baking powder Kosher salt 1/2 cup water 1/2 cup vodka 1 head cauliflower, cut into 1-inch florets 1/3 cup hot sauce, such as Frank&amp;rsquo;s 1 medium clove garlic, minced 1/4 cup picked celery leaves (optional) Instructions Preheat oil to 350°F in a large wok, Dutch oven, or deep fryer. Combine cornstarch, flour, baking powder, and 2 teaspoons kosher salt in a large bowl and whisk until homogeneous.</description></item><item><title>Mushroom and sausage pasta bake</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/mushroom-and-sausage-pasta-bake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/mushroom-and-sausage-pasta-bake/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup Panko-style bread crumbs 6 ounces grated Parmesan cheese 1/4 cup chopped fresh parsley leaves 2 tablespoons finely minced fresh chives 2 small shallots, finely minced (about 1/2 cup) 2 medium cloves garlic, minced (about 2 teaspoons) 2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper 2 tablespoons unsalted butter 8 ounces Italian sausage (mild or hot), removed from casings 1 pound mixed mushrooms (such as portobello, shiitake, and oyster), cleaned and thinly sliced 1 tablespoon soy sauce 1 tablespoon juice from 1 lemon 2 1/2 tablespoons all-purpose flour 2 cups homemade or store-bought low-sodium chicken stock 1 cup heavy cream 12 ounces fresh or 8 ounces dried ridged pasta such as rotini or campanelle Instructions Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and keep at a bare simmer.</description></item><item><title>Reverse braised beef</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/reverse-braised-beef/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/reverse-braised-beef/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 kg beef chuck or oyster blade 1 tbsp vinegar 1 tbsp sugar 1 tsp soy sauce oil salt pepper Instructions Place the meat in the pressure cooker. Pour in enough water to almost cover the meat, and cook on high pressure for 45 minutes with natural steam release. Gently fish the meat out of the pan, breaking it up as little as possible, and let the pieces dry/steam-off on paper towels for a few minutes.</description></item><item><title>Southern fried chicken</title><link>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/southern-fried-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://recipes.danielmentiplay.com/eat/southern-fried-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons paprika 2 tablespoons freshly ground black pepper 2 teaspoons garlic powder 2 teaspoons dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1 cup buttermilk 1 large egg 1/4 tsp kosher salt One whole chicken, about 4 pounds, cut into 10 pieces or 3 1/2 pounds bone-in, skin-on breasts, legs, drumsticks, and/or wings 1 1/2 cups all purpose flour 1/2 cup cornstarch 1 teaspoon baking powder 4 cups vegetable shortening or peanut oil Instructions Combine the paprika, black pepper, garlic powder, oregano, and cayenne in a small bowl and mix thoroughly with a fork.</description></item></channel></rss>